Faculty Wives Club of Xavier University records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Faculty Wives Club of Xavier University records
1955-1991
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Faculty Wives Club.
1 linear feet (2 Boxes)
This is a small collection of various records of the Faculty Wives Club of Xavier University. These records include their constitution, meeting minutes, reports, newsletters, correspondence, financial information, fliers and invitations for social events sponsored by the club, and photographs.
XUA-81
History of the Faculty Wives Club of Xavier University
The Faculty Wives Club of Xavier University was founded in 1955. The club existed to foster social relationships and a community of prayer between the administration and faculty members and their wives. This club hosted and sponsored many social activities including dances such as square dances, clam and lobster bakes, prayer services, and bridge marathons. In the Fall of 1982, it was proposed that the name be changed to the D'Artagnan Club to be more inclusive. This change was reflected in the 1983 Newsletter. These records end in 1991, and it is believed that this club disbanded at about that time.
Scope and Content
These records consist of the fliers and correspondence pertaining to the activities of the Faculty Wives of Club Xavier University as well as minutes, newsletters, and reports created to document these activities. A limited number of photographs are also included. Many documents came from the files maintained by the presidents of the club during their terms in office.
Statement of Arrangement
These records are divided into the following series:
Series I: Organizational Documents
Series II: Minutes
Series III: Newsletters
Series IV: General Information and Events
Restrictions on Access
There are no restrictions on access.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Faculty Wives Club; Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). D'Artagnan Club
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Series I: Organizational Documents, 1956-1973
  - Faculty Wives Club of Xavier University Constitution, (Includes Amendments and changes), 1956-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Procedure Manual (First Draft), Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series II: Minutes, 1955-1980
  - Faculty Wives of Xavier Minutes, 1955-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Wives of Xavier Minutes, 1961-1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Wives of Xavier Minutes, 1971-1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series III: Newsletters, 1971-1987
  - Xavier Wifeline/D'Artagnan Club [Newsletter], 1971-1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series IV: General Information and Events, 1956-1991
  - Faculty Wives Club, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Wives Club, 1958-1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Xavier University Faculty Wives Club, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Wives Club of Xavier University, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Faculty Wives of Xavier, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Faculty Wives Club of Xavier University 1970-1971 President's File, Sue Hellkamp (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Xavier Faculty Wives President's File, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Xavier Faculty Wives 1972-1973 President's File, Mrs. William Jones, President (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Wives of Xavier, 1973-1974; Mrs. Constantine Soriano (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Wives Club, 1974-1975; Contains photographs (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Xavier Faculty Wives, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Wives (Includes Presidents' Reports), 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Faculty Wives of Xavier, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - D'Artagnan Club 1983-1984, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - D'Artagnan Club, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - D'Artagnan Club, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - D'Artagnan Club, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - D'Artagnan Club 1987-1988, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - D'Artagnan Club, 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Faculty Wives Club Spring Dances, 1964-1969 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Faculty Wives Club Spring Dances, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Xavier Faculty Wives Club New Year's Eve Dances, 1965-1974 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Faculty Wives Club Christmas Parties, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Xavier Faculty Wives Children's Christmas Parties, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Xavier Faculty Wives Club Square Dance & Fall Picnic, 1964-1979 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - D'Artagnan Club Square Dance Report - 1984 (President's Copy) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - D'Artagnan Club Square Dance Reports, 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Faculty Wives Flyers and Invitations, 1956-1980 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Joanne Bonvillan Memorial Fund, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Photographs, 1960, 1962, 1964, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)